American Colony in Jerusalem Collection
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part III: Bertha Spafford Vester Files, 1861-1991 (Box III:1-III:9)
  - Speeches and writings (Box III:8)
    - Writings
      - Our Jerusalem
        - Draft, undated, (5 folders) (Box III:9)
        - Notes, undated
      - “Wardy”
        - Draft, undated
        - Tales told by the Arabs, undated
- Part III: John D. Whiting Files, 1906-1924 (Box III:10-III:11)
  Catalogues, correspondence, permits and passes, writings, and other papers relating primarily to John D. Whiting.
  - Antiquities catalogues (Box III:10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1913, undated, (2 folders)
    - Pottery collected by John D. Whiting, 1906-1910, (2 folders)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1924
  - Financial statement, 1917-1918
  - Letterbook, 1919-1925
  - Pass to Constantinople, 1909
  - Photograph of Whiting family, undated
  - World War I era items
    - Army book, 1918
    - A Brief Record of the Advance of the Egyptian Expeditionary Force under the Command of General Sir Edmund H. H. Allenby, G.C.B., G.C.M.G., July 1917 to October 1918, 1919
    - Miscellany, 1915-1919 (Box III:11)
    - Permits and passes, 1916-1920
  - Writings, 1913-1915, 1920, undated, (3 folders)
- Part III: Valentine Vester Files, 1989-2007 (Box III:11-III:19)
  Correspondence, newspaper clippings, photographs, and other papers.
  - American Colony Hotel, 1989-1995, 2002-2004 (Box III:11)
  - Birthday tributes, 1992
  - Correspondence
    - 1990
    - 1991, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box III:12)
    - 1992-1995, 2002-2004, undated
  - Miscellany, 1989-2004, (3 folders)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - 1989-1990, (7 folders)
    - 1991
      - Jan.-Mar., (3 folders)
      - Apr.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box III:13)
    - 1992, (6 folders)
    - 1993-1994, (10 folders) (Box III:14)
    - 1995-1996, (8 folders) (Box III:15)
    - 1997
      - Jan.-Apr., (2 folders)
      - May-Dec., (3 folders) (Box III:16)
    - 1998-1999, (8 folders)
    - 2000, (6 folders) (Box III:17)
    - 2001
      - Jan.-July, (3 folders)
      - Aug.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box III:18)
    - 2002, (6 folders)
    - 2003
      - Jan.-Mar.
      - Apr.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box III:19)
    - 2004-2005, (5 folders)
  - Notes, undated
  - Photographs, Matsson, Vester, and Whiting families, 2006-2007
- Part III: Miscellany, 1879-1997 (Box III:19-III:21)
  Diary, hymn book, notebooks, photographs, writings, and other items.
  - Account of 1967 Israel-Arab War by Frieda Ward, 1967 (Box III:19)
  - Cards and invitation, 1908, 1917
  - Diary kept by Mary Louise Adams (Sister Miriam), 1930-1931
  - Hymn book, annotated by Horatio Gates Spafford (1828-1888), 1879 (Box III:20)
  - Notebooks
    - Spafford, Anna, 1903-1918
    - Spafford, Jacob, includes copies of letters received, 1927-1932
  - Photographs
    - Jerusalem, Bethlehem, Sea of Galilee, 1947, 1965, undated, (2 folders)
    - People, 1890, 1904, 1912-1913, 1927-1930, circa 1960s, undated See also Oversize, (2 folders)
    - Tourist photos, 1950s-1960s
    - Visit to Sweden by Christina Larsson and Grace Whiting, 1967
  - Receipt, 1897
  - Samaritan manuscript, undated See Oversize
  - Writings about the American Colony, 1921-1923, 1931-1936, 1950, 1981-1997, undated, (11 folders) (Box III:21)
- Part III: Oversize, 1918-1967 (Box III:OV 1-III:OV 3)
  Photographs, scrapbook, prints, printed matter, and a Samaritan manuscript.
  - Bertha Spafford Vester Files (Box III:OV 1)
    - Miscellany
      - Prints and printed matter, 1918, 1958, undated (Container 6)
      - Scrapbooks, 1963-1967 (Container 7) (Box III:OV 2)
  - Miscellany (Box III:OV 3)
    - Photographs
      - People, 1927, circa 1960s, undated (Container 20)
    - Samaritan manuscript, undated (Container 20)